Finding Aid for Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Lucille B. Conger Alumnae Group (University of Michigan) records, 1947-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Lucille B. Conger Alumnae Group (University of Michigan) records 1947-2004, 1967-1996
University of Michigan. Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Lucille B. Conger Alumnae Group.
(in 3 boxes)
2.5 linear feet
04138 Bimu H6 2
The Lucile B. Conger Alumnae Chapter was established in 1947 as an offshoot of the Junior Michigan Alumnae Group. The Conger Chapter provides financial support and mentorship to women attending the University of Michigan through annual fundraising and social events. Materials include officer records, newsletters, membership directories, and scrapbooks.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated in October 2004. (Donor # 9518 ).
University records are public records and once fully processed are generally open to research use. Records that contain personally identifiable information will be restricted to protect individual privacy. The restriction of university records is subject to compliance with applicable laws.
The Lucile B. Conger Alumnae Chapter was founded in 1947 by members of the Junior Michigan Alumnae Group. Originally a branch of the Jr. Alums, the chapter was named after Lucile B. Conger, an executive secretary for the alumnae office and mentor to the group, upon her retirement. The Conger chapter is one of four UM alumnae chapters located in Ann Arbor, MI. It is directly affiliated with the Alumnae Council and the University of Michigan Alumni Association and participates in the events of the larger groups.
First fundraising efforts for the group were a cookbook sale and selling merchandise through the Alumnae Office. These have expanded to include annual events such as a fashion show, auction, attic sale, holiday home tour, and the Conger Ball. In 2004, these activities allowed the Conger Chapter to provide ten scholarships to female University of Michigan students. Partnerships with the Office of Financial Aid, the Athletic Department, and the Center for the Education of Women help the chapter meet a variety of needs. In addition, the group puts on numerous social and mentoring events throughout the year.
The collection is divided into four series, Officer Records, Newsletters, Directories, and Visual Materials.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Lucile B. Conger Group.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; University of Michigan. Alumnae Council.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Conger, Lucile B.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)
- Officer Records 1949-2004
  The Officer Records series (1.25 linear ft.) consists of meeting minutes, annual reports, event planning materials, scholarship information, and materials documenting the chapter’s participation in the UM Alumnae Council. It is organized by academic year.
  - 1949/50-1953/54 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Marge Mundus 1967/68 (Box 1)
  - Pres. May a Savarino 1970/71 (Box 1)
  - 1972/73-1973/74 (Box 1)
  - 1974/75-1975/76 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Kathy Hentschel 1976/77 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Dorothy Farhat 1977/78 (Box 1)
  - 1982/83-1983/84 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Anne Rubin 1984/85 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Ibbie Boehnke 1985/86
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meetings and Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Barb Hensinger 1986/87
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Branch 1987/88
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Gail Lozelle 1988/89
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Vilnius 1989/90
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes and Scholarship Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Kuehn 1990/91
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Events and Reports (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
  - Pres. Nancy Schleicher 1991/92
    - Alumnae Council and Scholarships (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Peggy DeJonckheere 1992/93
    - Alumnae Council (Box 1)
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes, Reports, and Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Pres. Sherry McClain 1993/94
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Dusti Beaubien 1994/95 (Box 1)
  - 1995/96 (Box 1)
  - 1996/97 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Trish Sandstrom 2001/02
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes and Reports (Box 1)
  - Pres. Cindy Valerio 2002/03
    - Events (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - Member Survey (Box 1)
  - Co-Pres. Maureen Kesselring and Janet Graydosh 2003/04 (Box 1)
- Newsletters 1952-2004
  The Newsletters series (.25 linear ft.) contains newsletters published between 4 and 6 times a year. These discuss chapter fundraising, events, and news about members.
  - 1952-1955 (Box 2)
  - 1956-1961 (Box 2)
  - 1967-1976 (Box 2)
  - 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - 1990-1997 (Box 2)
  - 2000-2004 (Box 2)
- Directories 1969-2004
  The Directories series (.25 linear ft.) consists of three folders containing annual member directories and information for officers and committee heads.
  - Officer Directories 1969-1986 (Box 2)
  - Member Directories 1949/50-1982/83 (scattered) (Box 2)
  - Member Directories 1983/84-2003/04 (scattered) (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks and Clippings 1947-1997
  The Scrapbooks and Clippings series (.75 linear ft) consists of 2 oversize scrapbooks. These albums contain newspapers clippings and photographs for much of the chapter’s history. There are also two folders of loose clippings and photographs.
  - Loose Newspaper Clippings 1947-1999 (Box 2)
  - Loose Photographs 1960, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook 1947-1956 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook 1947-1997 (Box 3)